<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Vin Souza (@tryvin)</title>
    <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Vin Souza (@tryvin)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:34:07 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vinsouza.work/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration and Maintance of Linux Servers at the AWS Stack</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/migration-and-maintance-of-linux-servers-at-the-aws-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:34:07 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/migration-and-maintance-of-linux-servers-at-the-aws-stack/</guid>
      <description>To discur here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Salesforce Sentiment Analysis System for Classifying best business opportunities</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/salesforce-sentiment-analysis-system-for-classifying-best-business-opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:33:30 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/salesforce-sentiment-analysis-system-for-classifying-best-business-opportunities/</guid>
      <description>To discur here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid using React Native and Electron for a POS System</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/hybrid-using-react-native-and-electron-for-a-pos-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:32:46 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/hybrid-using-react-native-and-electron-for-a-pos-system/</guid>
      <description>To discur here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migration and Maintenance of Linux Servers</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/migration-and-maintenance-of-linux-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:31:42 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/migration-and-maintenance-of-linux-servers/</guid>
      <description>To discur here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration with Brazilian&#39;s Eletronic Tax Systems</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/integration-with-brazilians-eletronic-tax-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:30:55 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/integration-with-brazilians-eletronic-tax-systems/</guid>
      <description>To discur here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>POS Version with QT for offline usage</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/pos-version-with-qt-for-offline-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:30:21 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/pos-version-with-qt-for-offline-usage/</guid>
      <description>To discur here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>POS System running at a Cloud Stack</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/pos-system-running-at-a-cloud-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:29:30 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/pos-system-running-at-a-cloud-stack/</guid>
      <description>To discur here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pure Android Dating App</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/pure-android-dating-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:34:38 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/pure-android-dating-app/</guid>
      <description>This was my first Android project, using Java and pure Android code.
We hired a external company to do our app, but they were taking too long. That said, that&amp;rsquo;s where I enter.
I got the project from their hands, the project had barely started, and had to join forces with the web designer we had in the company to make this app come to live.
Had many challenges working with this app, first Android app, first lots of images and contents mobile app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implement Notifications System on top of live chat system</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/implement-notifications-system-on-top-of-live-chat-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:31:55 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/implement-notifications-system-on-top-of-live-chat-system/</guid>
      <description>After the live chat project was done, I had another challenge, add a layer to the notifications alerts.
Using the PHP backend as the entry point, Python was able to retrieve users notifications, and send them to the connected clients.
This gave us the ability to notify users about their own notifications, and the ability to give users a general warning in less then 10 seconds.
Users received the notification in milli-seconds as long as they were connected with the WebSocket systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real Time Chat Engine using Python and Tornado</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/real-time-chat-engine-using-python-and-tornado/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:27:26 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/real-time-chat-engine-using-python-and-tornado/</guid>
      <description>Pessoas.vc was running at Facebook, and one of the main goals to run there was to have a local chat for the users, where they could chat real time, without the hassle of page reloads, or COMET requests.
At the time, Facebook had bought FriendFeed and released FriendFeed HTTP Server and Framework to the wild.
Using them a combination of WebSockets, Python, and Tornado, I was able to integrate the internal PHP backend with the Live Chat process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create a In-House parser for OpenSocial canvas XML</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/create-a-in-house-parser-for-opensocial-canvas-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:22:29 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/create-a-in-house-parser-for-opensocial-canvas-xml/</guid>
      <description>After we launched at Orkut, we had to expand, and the next social network at our list was MySpace.
We then had to do some small changes here and there to accommodate the users and their own stack.
First thing was to integrate the OpenSocial login we had from Orkut to MySpace, even thought they had joined forces to create the OpenSocial consortium, the thing wasn&amp;rsquo;t really working the same way to all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a In-House CDN for Images</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/creating-a-in-house-cdn-for-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:14:37 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/creating-a-in-house-cdn-for-images/</guid>
      <description>We had a huge issue, the images were being stored in a single server, and that said, we had to migrate this to a distributed servers architecture.
At the time, I had researched some of the best CDNs available, but they all lacked one thing: &amp;ldquo;low prices&amp;rdquo;. Working on a budget means being creative, and some times, you need to do it right, and do it first.
After presenting the options we had to the members board, we decided to go with a different approach: &amp;ldquo;Let&amp;rsquo;s copy some of these guys and do our own CDN&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dating Application for Orkut</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/dating-application-for-orkut/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:08:30 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/dating-application-for-orkut/</guid>
      <description>My work with StayTrack got out, and a local entrepreneur got in contact.
He said he were seeking for someone with knowledge with PHP to be one of the first developers into his company&amp;rsquo;s team.
The project was: A Dating App for Orkut, at the time, the main social network at Brazil and India, one of a kind. Facebook wasn&amp;rsquo;t even born yet.
At this project I learned more and more about the high performance systems, we launched with a boom from a local TV show, and the audience was huge, we had to keep thing running, and didn&amp;rsquo;t have too much resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation of Announcements and Software Modules</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/translation-of-announcements-and-software-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:03:23 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/translation-of-announcements-and-software-modules/</guid>
      <description>When I first met Linux I felt in love with the K Desktop Environment, and this love got me to the spirit of helping and community.
With small steps, I got into the Brazilian KDE community, and started translating the KDE Announcements from English to Brazilian Portuguese.
As soon as the official announcements were release, we had 1 hour tops to get them translated, so the project could start their own promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Proxy with Squid to improve performance</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/reverse-proxy-with-squid-to-improve-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 22:52:31 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/reverse-proxy-with-squid-to-improve-performance/</guid>
      <description>The company had a big issue, their static pages were being served by the internal IIS server.
At the time, IIS wasn&amp;rsquo;t really improved as what we have today. My job was to discover how to reduce the company site loading time, in order to improve the user experience.
After some hours of debugging I found that the main culprit were pages that could simply be cached and served by a reverse proxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Car Tracking for the Customers</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/live-car-tracking-for-the-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 22:49:23 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/live-car-tracking-for-the-customers/</guid>
      <description>Using PHP and Google Maps API I handled the integration with the proprietary car tracking system used by the staff.
Using ACLs to control what the clients were able to see, and which cars they were allowed to see, I arranged a nice and direct interface, so the clients could just login, choose their cars, and track them real time.
With this project I was able to reduce the number of phone calls to the customer central by 70%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squid Proxy at IFS</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/squid-proxy-at-ifs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 21:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/squid-proxy-at-ifs/</guid>
      <description>This was one of my first projects at IFS, setting up and keeping it running smoothly to handle the user network traffic from the whole institute.
Made us save 40% on bandwidth, with good network rules, caching Windows updates, and Anti-virus updates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>