<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Vin Souza (@tryvin)</title>
    <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Vin Souza (@tryvin)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:03:23 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vinsouza.work/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation of Announcements and Software Modules</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/translation-of-announcements-and-software-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 23:03:23 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/translation-of-announcements-and-software-modules/</guid>
      <description>When I first met Linux I felt in love with the K Desktop Environment, and this love got me to the spirit of helping and community.
With small steps, I got into the Brazilian KDE community, and started translating the KDE Announcements from English to Brazilian Portuguese.
As soon as the official announcements were release, we had 1 hour tops to get them translated, so the project could start their own promotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Proxy with Squid to improve performance</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/reverse-proxy-with-squid-to-improve-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 22:52:31 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/reverse-proxy-with-squid-to-improve-performance/</guid>
      <description>The company had a big issue, their static pages were being served by the internal IIS server.
At the time, IIS wasn&amp;rsquo;t really improved as what we have today. My job was to discover how to reduce the company site loading time, in order to improve the user experience.
After some hours of debugging I found that the main culprit were pages that could simply be cached and served by a reverse proxy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Car Tracking for the Customers</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/live-car-tracking-for-the-customers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2018 22:49:23 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/live-car-tracking-for-the-customers/</guid>
      <description>Using PHP and Google Maps API I handled the integration with the proprietary car tracking system used by the staff.
Using ACLs to control what the clients were able to see, and which cars they were allowed to see, I arranged a nice and direct interface, so the clients could just login, choose their cars, and track them real time.
With this project I was able to reduce the number of phone calls to the customer central by 70%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Squid Proxy at IFS</title>
      <link>https://vinsouza.work/project/squid-proxy-at-ifs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2018 21:38:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vinsouza.work/project/squid-proxy-at-ifs/</guid>
      <description>This was one of my first projects at IFS, setting up and keeping it running smoothly to handle the user network traffic from the whole institute.
Made us save 40% on bandwidth, with good network rules, caching Windows updates, and Anti-virus updates.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>